Finding Aid for Fletcher, Pack and Company (Alpena, Mich.) Records, 1868-ca. 1923
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Fletcher, Pack and Company (Alpena, Mich.) Records 1868-circa 1923, 1868-1898
Fletcher, Pack and Company (Alpena, Mich.)
17 oversize volumes
4.3 linear feet
85633 Bb.2/2; BB.2 Outsize
Fletcher, Pack and Company and A. F. Fletcher & Company were two early Alpena, Michigan lumber companies. Financial, land, and other business records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were the gift of Mr. Philip Kingsbury Fletcher (donor no. 17 ). The Fletcher, Pack & Co. records were received in 1950. The A. F. Fletcher Co. records were received in 1953.
The record group is open to research.
The Fletcher, Pack and Company of Alpena, Michigan was founded by George W. Fletcher and Albert Pack; the A. F. Fletcher & Company was founded by Addison F. Fletcher, who operated a sawmill.
This record group includes financial records, records of land purchases, and other miscellaneous business materials. There are also some photographs detailing scenes of lumbering activities. Although described here together, these are the records of separate Fletcher family companies: Fletcher, Pack Company and the A. F. Fletcher Company. The relationship between these two companies is not clear.
Related Materials
The researcher is directed to the records of the Fletcher Family, the Thunder Bay Boom Company, and the Gilchrist family for related material.
Subjects:
Alpena (Mich.); Business records.; Fletcher, Pack and Company (Alpena, Mich.); Logging--Michigan--Alpena.; Lumbering--Michigan--Alpena.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Business enterprises--Michigan--Alpena.; Alpena Sulphate Fibre Company.; Arizona.; Bridges.; Alpena (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Dams.; Fletcher, Pack and Company (Alpena, Mich.); Floods--Michigan--Alpena--1923.; Hinda (Ship); Laborers.; Lumber industry--Michigan--Alpena.; Maine.; Marine accidents.; Mining--Arizona.; Portland Cement Company (Alpena, Mich.); Power plants--Maine--Rumford Falls--1894.; Quarrying--Michigan.; Railroads--Michigan.; Shipping--Great Lakes.; Ships--Great Lakes.; Stephen C. Hall (Ship)
Contributors:
A. F. Fletcher & Company (Alpena, Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Fletcher, Pack and Company business records
  - Correspondence regarding taxes 1888-1890 (Box 1)
  - Tax and Land records, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Tax certificates, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning business venture in Appleton, Wisconsin 1890 (Box 1)
  - Land purchase record book (Box 1)
  - Record of land purchases 1879-1892 (Box 1)
  - Petty ledger 1879-1881 (Box 1)
  - Petty ledger 1882-1884 (Box 1)
  - Petty ledger 1888-1892 (Box 1)
  - Index to Petty ledgers (Volume 1)
  - Index to Petty ledgers (Volume 2)
    (continued)
  - Index to Petty ledgers (Volume 3)
  - Index to Petty ledgers (Volume 4)
  - Lands conveyed to company by Alpena County (Box 1)
  - Misc. papers 1880s (Box 1)
- Fletcher, Pack and Company Day Books
  - September 1879-June 1880 (Box 2)
  - June-December 1880 (Box 2)
  - December 1880-June 1881 (Box 2)
  - June-December 1881 (Box 2)
  - January-August 1882 (Box 2)
  - August 1882-May 1883 (Box 3)
  - May-December 1883 (Box 3)
  - January-October 1884 (Box 3)
  - October 1884-July 1885 (Box 3)
  - July 1885-March 1886 (Box 3)
  - April-December 1886 (Box 4)
  - December 1886-September 1887 (Box 4)
  - September 1887-December 1888 (Volume 5)
  - December 1888-August 1890 (Volume 6)
  - September 1890-January 1898 (Volume 7)
- Fletcher, Pack and Company Ledgers
  - September 1879-February 1882 (Volume 8)
  - March 1882-December 1885 (Volume 9)
  - January 1886-December 1888 (Volume 10)
  - January 1889-January 1898 (Volume 11)
- A. F. Fletcher and Company
  - Journal October 1868-May 1872 (Volume 12)
  - Journal May 1872-July 1877 (Volume 13)
  - Journal July 1877-January 1881 (Volume 14)
  - Ledger October 1868-May 1872 (Volume 15)
  - Ledger May 1872-July 1877 (Volume 16)
  - Ledger July 1877-November 1879 (Volume 17)
  - Ledger 1868-1881 (Box 5)
- Photographs, circa 1892-1923
  - Lumbering, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Mining; miscellaneous (Box 5)
    (include Rumsford Falls, Maine)
  - Flood (Box 5)
  - Ships (Box 5)